<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travels on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</title>
    <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/travels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travels on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/travels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Caribbeans</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/travels/caribbeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/travels/caribbeans/</guid>
      <description>Anguilla Antigua Aruba Barbados Bonaire Caymans Curaçao Dominica Grenada Guadeloupe Martinique St. Barts St. Kitts &amp;amp; Nevis St. Lucia Turks &amp;amp; Caicos  Connections between isles     Brief and vague description of some Caribbean islands&amp;rsquo; tourism and environment.
Anguilla Great beaches, expensive, little to do, low-key vibe
Antigua Green, good beaches, some history, medium expensive
Aruba Lunar-looking, arid, great beaches, mostly resorts, no history, somewhat affordable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Polynesia</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/travels/french_polynesia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/travels/french_polynesia/</guid>
      <description>Sort of ideal itinerary for a 10-15 days trip.
Not to miss  Huahine Bora Bora Moorea Nuku Hiva (one of the Marquesas)  Nice to go  Rangiroa (an atoll) Fakarava (another atoll) Mauputi (a cheaper alternative to Bora Bora, very similar to it) Raiatea (rocky) Taha&amp;rsquo;a (next to Bora Bora, similar as it is an atoll around a rocky and mountainous island) Tikehau (another atoll, next to Rangiroa) Mataiva (an arid atoll, next to Tikehau)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Places to Visit</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/travels/places_to_visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/travels/places_to_visit/</guid>
      <description>Europe  Cyprus  Ayia Napa beaches Protaras beaches   Croatia  Best beaches Croatian tour agencies   Malta  Maltese best beaches   Portugal  Portugal beaches     Africa  Egypt   Americas  Mexico  Cenotes Best beaches     Asia  Indonesia * Bali Thailand  Bangkok Pattaya       Europe Cyprus Ayia Napa beaches  Nissi Makronisos Grecian Bay  Protaras beaches  Fig Tree Bay Cape Greco  Croatia Best beaches  Baska - on Krk Girandella - Rabac Brela - north of Makarska Supetar - on Brac Zlatni Rat - on Brac Plat - south of Dubrovnik, near Brasina  Croatian tour agencies  Adriatic Explore Atlas Croatia  Malta Maltese best beaches  Armier Bay Balluta/St.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
