<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy and Religion on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</title>
    <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy and Religion on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buddhism</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/buddhism/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/buddhism/index.html</guid>
      <description>Contacts between Buddhism and Christianity Similitudes between Buddhism and Western philosophies Hegesians Dionysus in India Contacts between Buddhism and Christianity One one of the major Ashoka&amp;rsquo;s rock edicts, (the 13th), it is stated how a few ellenistic kings were followers of the Dhamma. One of them is Ptolemy II and his sister Arsinoe II.
In the apocryphal Gospel of Thomas, at verse 90, Jesus says:
Come unto me, for my yoga is natural and my lordship is gentle—and you shall find repose for yourselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christianity</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/christianity/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/christianity/index.html</guid>
      <description>Random facts Apocryphal books Book of Jubilees Book of Enoch Apocryphal Gospels Gospel of James Infancy Gospel of Thomas Gospel of Pseudo-Matthew Gospel of the Ebionites Gospel of the Hebrews Gospel of the Nazarenes Gospel of Marcion Gospel of Mani Gospel of Peter Gospel of Nicodemus Questions of Bartholomew Apocryphon of James Book of Thomas the Contender Dialogue of the Savior Gospel of Judas Gospel of Mary Gospel of Philip Greek Gospel of the Egyptians Gospel of Truth Pistis Sophia Second Treatise of the Great Seth Apocryphon of John Apocalypse of Paul First Apocalypse of James Second Apocalypse of James Apocalypse of Pseudo-Methodius Apocalypse of Peter Early Christianity Chrolonogy Theological facts Non-theological facts Antisemitism Other facts Marcion of Sinope = founder of Marcionism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hinduism</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/hinduism/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/hinduism/index.html</guid>
      <description>Philosophical schools within Hinduism Cārvāka - contemporary school to Buddha&amp;rsquo;s lifetime, which has arguably influenced his teachings. Materialistic, skeptic, atheist. Samkhya - one of the most ancient schools, already rejecting the concept of an unitary God (Ishvara). </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/philosophy/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/philosophy/index.html</guid>
      <description>Eliminative materialism/Eliminativism Notable philosphers of Eliminativism References Moral Nihilism Notable philosophers of Moral Nihilism Existential Nihilism Eliminative materialism/Eliminativism In general, eliminativism refers to the class of views in sciences that deny the existence of some entities. In the philosophy of mind realm, Eliminativism means the denial of existence of various states of the mind, such as belief or desire. It postulates how no scientifical basis for the existence of these states will ever be found.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paganism</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/paganism/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/paganism/index.html</guid>
      <description>Greek Paganism Roman Paganism Nordic Paganism Greek Paganism Certain deities, in particular Zeus and Poseidon, were never depicted by images during the Archaic period (cit. A History of Pagan Europe, ch 2, pg 85)
Roman Paganism Varro tells us that the early Romans worshipped their deities without images. The basic Roman belief seems to have been in numen or supernatural power rather than in personified spirits (cit. A History of Pagan Europe, ch 3, pg 52)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yoga</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/yoga/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/yoga/index.html</guid>
      <description> Random Facts Random Facts Developed since the Indus civilization times Codified in sutras by Patanjali (around 1550 b.C.), with buddhistic influences Hatha Yoga (born in 900 a.C. but fully developed in 1400 by Yogi Swatmarama): introduces many postures, increases the importance of purifying the mind through the purification of the body </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zealots</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/zealots/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/philosophy_and_religion/zealots/index.html</guid>
      <description>Random facts
Jewish sect, formed around 6 b.C. Strong opposers of Roman domination.
Characteristics
Simon, one of the apostles, was called &amp;ldquo;the zealot&amp;rdquo; The Zealots waited for the coming of the King of the World Strong messianic beliefs Preference for the Maccabees books over all other ones. Those books aren&amp;rsquo;t considered canonical by some protestant churches and are thus only after the Trent Council for catholics Zealots were killed off after the Bar Kochba insurrection of 131 a.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>