<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Science Theory on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</title>
    <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Science Theory on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Oh Notation</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/theory/big_oh_notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/theory/big_oh_notation/</guid>
      <description>Basic definitions  O(1) = constant: the operation doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on the size of its input O(n) = linear: the run time complexity is proportionate to the size of n O(log n) = logarithmic: normally associated with algorithms that break the problem into smaller chunks O(n log n) = just n log n: usually associated with an algorithm that breaks the problem into smaller chunks per each invocation, and then takes the results of the smaller chunks and stitches them back together O(n²) = quadratic O(n³) = cubic  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Structures</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/theory/data_structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/theory/data_structures/</guid>
      <description>Linked List  History   Queues Dynamic Array Skip List Binary Tree  BSP Tree Binary Indexed Tree   Heap Associative Array Bit Array Trie Record Union Set   Linked List A linked list is a collection of elements whose order is not given by the physical placement in memory but each element points to the next.
Each element, or node, contains both data and a reference to the next node in the sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Theory</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/theory/set_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/theory/set_theory/</guid>
      <description>Basics  A ⊆ B = A is a subset of B. All the members of A are also found in B A ∪ B = Union. All the elements that are in A, B or both A ∩ B = Intersection. All the elements that are both in A and B A⊂ = Complement or Absolute complement. The set of all elements that are not in A but are in U, which is the universal set, basically a superset of all sets defined A⊂ ∩ B = Relative complement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
