<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</title>
    <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/health/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autism</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/health/autism/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/health/autism/index.html</guid>
      <description>A few notes on the effects/causes of autism on/due to the brain.
Study on the effects of serotonin receptors on the Gut-Brain Microbiome in Autism Spectrum disorders Gut disfunctions occur at a four-fold greater rate in individuals with autism spectrum disorder than in normal population. Correlation found between autism spectrum disorders, especially connected to language-impairment, and constipation. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depression</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/health/depression/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/health/depression/index.html</guid>
      <description>A few notes on the effects/causes of depression on/due to the brain.
Mostly coming from The Upward Spiral book
Depressed subjects have less dopamine activity in the nucleus accumbens Dorsal striatum has strong ties with the nucleus accumbens Dopamine released in dorsal striatum doesn&amp;rsquo;t increase feelings of pleasure Patterns in the dorsal striatum can&amp;rsquo;t be erased, ever Serotonin is not unlimited Inhibiting an impulse uses serotonin The dopamine system helps modulating both slow-wave deep sleep and rem sleep Circadian rhythms influence the production of dopamine receptors, dopamine transponders and dopamine itself Depressed subjects have dysregulated oxytocin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/health/mental_health/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/health/mental_health/index.html</guid>
      <description>Various notes on possible issues to keep in mind.
Not Asking For Help: possible cause is none of value, or at all, is believed to be possibly received. Not Being Socially Active: probably due to the fact that if I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel loved by family, the assumption is that nobody else could love me. If neither my family loved me, why would anybody else do? Why bothering trying to find love in others then?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>