<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Scientia - Gianluca Fiore Knowledge Wiki</title>
    <link>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Scientia - Gianluca Fiore Knowledge Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Calligraphy</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/calligraphy/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/calligraphy/index.html</guid>
      <description>Styles Carolingian Foundational Visigothic Luxeuil Beneventan Insular Protogothic Humanist Times Trajan Rustic (Roman) Square Capitals (Roman) Business Cursive Spencerian Copperplate Merovingian Laon Round Hand Italic / Cancilleresca Secretary Hand Uncial Half-Uncial Artificial Uncial Neuland Capitals Gothic scripts Primitive/Early Gothic Textura Textus Quadratus Textus Prescissus Littera Textualis Littera Textualis Current Fraktur Rotunda Gothic Cursive Bastarda </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fountain Pens</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/fountain_pens/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/fountain_pens/index.html</guid>
      <description> Terminology Inks to try Wet inks for hard starter pens Terminology from The Graying Area
Inks to try Wet inks for hard starter pens deAtramentis Ferris Wheel Press Iroshizuku: Kon-Peki, Ama-iro, Shin-ryoku, Tsukushi Rohrer &amp;amp; Klingner Sailor Jentle: Rikyu-cha Waterman </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Writing</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/technical_writing/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/technical_writing/index.html</guid>
      <description>Types of Technical Documentation Product documentation API documentation SDK documentation Release Notes Engineering resources Process documentation / SOP Project plans Business standards Marketing and Sales documentation Market Requirements Documents (MRD) Request For Proposals (RFP) Scientific papers Terminology Books Writing and Technical Writing books Styling and Designing Content books Style guides Online documentation and courses Tools Confluence Useful Macros/Plugins Content reusing in Confluence Tips Help &amp;amp; Manual MadCap Flare Oxygen SDL Triton RoboHelp Scribus Framemaker Default DITA xml elements available in Framemaker How to change background colour of a paragraph Paligo Booktype Clickhelp HelpNDoc Markdoc MkDocs-Material Redocly Author-it Astoria Ovitas Document360 Doc-To-Help HelpStudio OfficeHelp Slate Google Drawing draw.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UX Writing</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/ux_writing/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Scientia/writing/ux_writing/index.html</guid>
      <description>Terminology Terminology Affinity Diagram Also called &amp;ldquo;affinity chart&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;affinity mapping&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;K-J method&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;thematic analysis&amp;rdquo;. It is a visual mapping of ideas into their natural relationships, often the output of a brainstorming session in a team. Card Sorting In UX researching, card sorting is a technique in which participants sort labels for content into larger categories. Thsi provides insight into how participants group a product&amp;rsquo;s content, how they associate different pieces of content, helping to design the information architecture.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>