<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hobbies on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</title>
    <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hobbies on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cigars</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/cigars/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/cigars/index.html</guid>
      <description>Cigars flavours Plants Spices and Herbs Earth and Minerals Fruits Nuts Flowers Other Not-Really-Flavor Flavors Brands I am not an heavy smoker by any statistics. I dislike cigarettes and vaping, never got into weed even. But cigars, I like them. Very rarely I smoke one, more often the small ones, cigarillos, rather than the chunky ones. One every 2-3 weeks, at most.
I am not a huge fan nor a conneisseur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fantasy</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/fantasy/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/fantasy/index.html</guid>
      <description>Chronology of fantasy of importance 1865: Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland is first published. 1922: E.R. Eddison&amp;rsquo;s The Worm Ouroboros is published. 1924: Lord Dunsany&amp;rsquo;s The King of Elfland&amp;rsquo;s Daughter is published. 1929-1930: Kull appears on Weird Tales. His character would end up inspiring the more famous Conan. Further stories would be published posthumously in the late 1960s-1970s. 1932-: Conan the Barbarian appears on Weird Tales in 1932. Main stories would be published throughout the 1930s, with a few posthumously being released during the 1950s and 1960s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malazan</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/malazan/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/malazan/index.html</guid>
      <description>Gardens of the Moon Deadhouse Gates Memories of Ice As a great fan of the Malazan Book of the Fallen fantasy series, I like to collect small notes and facts during my rereads. Here they are, as a curiosity or starting point of further researching.
The notes are separated by the book they are in, and ordered by page count.
Gardens of the Moon pg 352-359: K&amp;rsquo;rul helps a Rhivi woman and P&amp;rsquo;ran Chole to give birth to Silverfox in a dream of Kruppe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/music/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/music/index.html</guid>
      <description>Noticeable lyrics I rarely pay attention to lyrics. I am more focused on the music, the vibe, the technical skills of the instrumentalists rather than the words (and the singing as well). Occasionally a song catches my attention in an unusual way and then I go to read the lyrics.
More often than not, the lyrics aren&amp;rsquo;t that great but very, very rarely, they are. I will save here links to lyrics that are worth reading (and the song isn&amp;rsquo;t bad either).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sailing</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/sailing/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/hobbies/sailing/index.html</guid>
      <description>Things to know before a sailing course (ideally) Boats Good boats Cheap new boats Things to know before a sailing course (ideally) Sea terminology = parts of boat, rigging, sails Sail handling = bending on, setting, reefing, handling of sails, use of sheets, halyards and winches Ropework = coiling, stowing and securing to cleats and single/double bollards of ropes. Handling warps Knots = to learn figure-of-eight clove hitch rolling hitch bowline round turn two half hitches single sheet bend double sheet bend reef knot Fire and hazards = awareness and precautions to prevent fire, actions to take in the event of fire Rules for wearing safety harnesses, lifejackets and buoyancy aids Man overboard procedures Emergency equipment = how to operate and when to use distress flares, how to launch and board a life raft Manners and customs = use of burgees and ensigns, prevention of noise or disturbance, responsibilities to protect the environment Rules of passing and precedence Dinghies = loading rules, handling under oars Meteo = forecasting services knowledge, Beaufort scale Knowing and handling seasickness Helmanship = basic principles of sailing, steering and trimming sails on all points of sailing, steer a compass course under sail and power Responsibilities of skipper and crew Vessel checkout = documentation, charts, nautical publications and flags Capsizing, swamping and sinking Buoyage Charts, tides and currents Basic first-aid Anchoring and running aground Boats Good boats Nautor Swan 43 Oyster Mariner Hallberg Rassy Mistral Hallberg Rassy Monsun Hylas 44 (130-150k€ used) Kirie Feeling 486 (120-150k€ used) Hallberg Rassy 310 (190k€) Catalina 400 MkII (120-150k€) Dufour 36 (80-120k€ used) Dufour 38 Moody 41 DS (way too expensive&amp;hellip;) Sirius 35/40 Dehler 38SQ (170k€+) Cheap new boats Beneteau Oceanis 38.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>