<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</title>
    <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christianity</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/christianity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/christianity/</guid>
      <description>Marcion of Sinope = founder of Marcionism. First to develop a New Testament canon. Then declared heretic and forced the orthodox Church to develop their own canon. Therapeautae = a Christian sect in Alexandria from 1st century a.C. Their practices were similar to Theravada Buddhism and their name may have been an adaption to Greek of the pali word Theravada.  Apocryphal books  Book of Jubilees = only canon for the Ethiopian Church and the Ethiopian Jews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hinduism</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/hinduism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/hinduism/</guid>
      <description>Philosophical schools within Hinduism  Cārvāka - contemporary school to Buddha&amp;rsquo;s lifetime, which has arguably influenced his teachings. Materialistic, skeptic, atheist. Samkhya - one of the most ancient schools, already rejecting the concept of an unitary God (Ishvara).  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Military History</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/military_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/military_history/</guid>
      <description>Early Islamic Conquests Main notes  Caliph Umar didn&amp;rsquo;t want to invade Persia after occupying Iraq. He wished to retain the Mesopotamian area only but the ammassing of troops along the Zagros mountains and some Sassanid raids in southern Iraq forced him to act.  Khalid ibn Walid Originally an opposer to Muhammad, he was never a zealot in pushing Islam but more like a shrewd, bold and cunning military commander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/yoga/</guid>
      <description>Random facts
 Developed since the Indus civilization times Codified in sutras by Patanjali (around 1550 b.C.), with buddhistic influences Hatha Yoga (born in 900 a.C. but fully developed in 1400 by Yogi Swatmarama): introduces many postures, increases the importance of purifying the mind through the purification of the body  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zealots</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/zealots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/zealots/</guid>
      <description>Random facts
Jewish sect, formed around 6 b.C. Strong opposers of Roman domination.
Characteristics
 Simon, one of the apostles, was called &amp;ldquo;the zealot&amp;rdquo; The Zealots waited for the coming of the King of the World Strong messianic beliefs Preference for the Maccabees books over all other ones. Those books aren&amp;rsquo;t considered canonical by some protestant churches and are thus only after the Trent Council for catholics Zealots were killed off after the Bar Kochba insurrection of 131 a.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
