<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</title>
    <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Gianluca Fiore Personal Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Military History</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/military_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/military_history/</guid>
      <description>Early Islamic Conquests Main notes  Caliph Umar didn&amp;rsquo;t want to invade Persia after occupying Iraq. He wished to retain the Mesopotamian area only but the ammassing of troops along the Zagros mountains and some Sassanid raids in southern Iraq forced him to act.  Khalid ibn Walid Originally an opposer to Muhammad, he was never a zealot in pushing Islam but more like a shrewd, bold and cunning military commander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sumeria</title>
      <link>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/sumeria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://donearm.github.io/Personal-Wiki/history/sumeria/</guid>
      <description>Electronic Text Corpus of Sumerian Literature (ordered by date).
Interesting texts perused so far:
 Letter from Gudea to his god imploring support  with a nice ending quote My god, I am not one to be hostile. May you show sympathy towards me once again.   Nanshe and the birds Gilgamesh, Enkidu and the nether world Enlil and Sud Gilgamesh and Aga Ningishzida&amp;rsquo;s journey to the nether world Gilgamesh and Huwawa The Sumerian King List Enki&amp;rsquo;s journey to Nibiru Enlil and Ninlil Pabilsang&amp;rsquo;s journey to Nibru The Lament for Nibru The Sargon legend The cursing of Agade Lugalbanda The marriage of Martu  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
